BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

DEVOPS ENGINEER - STANDARD CHARTERED, CHENNAI

ONLINE

http://bharathkumarraju.com
in in.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraju

CONTACT Chennai,TamilNadu t: +91 9884579582

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com

BIO DETAILS

DOB: 12-June-1987 Passport: J7879295





SUMMARY:

Over **7 years** IT experience in **DevOps** and **Systems Engineer** in mission critical environments across the Financial and GPS industries. Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, **automation**, **continuous deployment(CICD)** pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

Able to communicate effectively at all levels and able to work on own initiative or within a larger group including during crisis situations.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Puppet, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Jenkins, gradle, nginx, liquibase.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash, Filebeats, metricbeat, packetbeat.

Monitoring/Log Sysdig,Newrelic,Datadog,AppDynamics,Sumologic.

Programming Python, Shell Scripts, Java.

RDBMS Oracle, MS SQL, Sybase, PostgreSQL, MySQL.
OS Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu.

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform.

Certifications AWS Solution Architect and VMware Cloud Professional

EXPERIENCE:

StandardChartered,

Chennai (Oct 2016-Present) Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline. Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic Stack. Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution.

Introduced Nginx as Gateway & Dockerized it with F5 as load Balancer.

Worked on Micro-service Architecture with spring config server for dynamic variable substitution in ansible.

Trimble Navigation,

Chennai

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform.

Created Development, QA, Stage, Production stacks & maintaining them securely using robust VPC design.

(Jun2014-Sep2016) Worked on REST API Development using AWS Gateway and AWS Lambda (Python).

Automated resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort. Implemented application monitoring using DataDog & integrated with AWS environment...

Involved in designing & Architecting the AWS environments from web to app to DB layers with caching.

Hewlett-Packard, Chennai

Performing Software installation, upgrade/patches, troubleshooting & maintenance on UNIX Servers.

Server installation/maintenance (SAN, NFS) with RAID.

(Mar2011-May2014) Administrated DHCP,DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Automating the deployment of Middleware Applications to RHEL DEV/PROD servers on VMWare ESX.

EDUCATION:

MCA-Post Graduation Information System and Computer Science

(Jun2007-Jun2010) UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

BSC- Graduation Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

(Jul2004-May2007) Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics.

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi.

INTERESTS:

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.